penguin.co.uk 2015-12-30

# Privacy Policy | Penguin Books UK

This web site is owned and operated by Penguin Books Limited.

### Our Privacy Policy

We want visitors to our websites to be able to take part fully in the activities and offers we provide. We also want to make sure that when we collect information from you, we do so in a way that does not infringe your right to privacy. This Privacy Policy is designed to give you useful information about the way we collect and use personal information and how we use cookies.

By using our websites you accept the terms of this Privacy Policy.

### Personal Information

We will not collect any personal data from you unless you specifically provide it and we will only use that information for the purposes to which you have consented. We do not ask you to provide any more information than is reasonably necessary to enable you to participate in an activity on our website and to improve the website.

We do not generally disclose your personal information to third parties. We may have to sometimes, in which case we will inform you of our intention to do so when we collect the information and you will have the opportunity to consent to that use or not.

Except as described in this Privacy Policy, we do not maintain any personal information obtained from users through this website in a retrievable form.

The information that we collect and how we use it

Below are some examples of when we might request your information and how we will use it.

### Newsletters

We have several newsletters that keep readers up-to-date with information on our books, authors, events, offers etc. If you would like to subscribe to one of our newsletters, we will require you to send us your email address so that we can send the newsletter to you. We may also ask you to provide other information about yourself, such as your name, age, sex and location so that we can personalise your newsletters.

### Prize Promotions

We regularly run competitions and prize draws and, in addition to your answer or entry, we will require you to send us certain information, such as your name and email address. We will only use this information to administer the promotion and for any other purpose to which you consented when you entered.

### Shopping

To be able to buy items from any of our online shops, we will require you to register an account with us. For this, we will ask you to provide your name, email address, a password and password reminder, your billing and delivery address and bank details. We use a third-party payment service to facilitate purchases through our site so, by providing us with your information, you consent to us passing that information to our payment service provided for the purpose of completing your transactions.

### Forums and User Content

If you sign up to one of our forums, we will ask you to provide a username and email address so that we can let people know who posts which comment and to enable us to deal with any inappropriate or offensive behaviour.

For the same reasons, if you provide comments on any articles or upload your own content to our sites, we may ask you to provide your email address.

Email and other contact details You may wish to contact us from time to time by sending us letters or emails or by filling in contact forms on one of our websites. We will only use this information to respond to your query or suggestion.

### Cookies

We use cookies on this site to enable certain parts of the site to function and to collect non-personal information about your use of the site so that we can improve our visitors' experience.

### What are Cookies?

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer or mobile device by websites that you visit. They cannot harm your computer and do not contain any information that enable us to identify you personally, they just enable our websites to recognise your computer and to identify certain other non-personal information such as which browser you are using. This information can be used to make the website work, to identify which parts of the site can work better or to analyse how often people visit the site and what they look at. We will not associate this data with any personally identifying information that you may choose to provide to us in other ways.

By your using this website, we imply that you have read this policy and agree to us sending you cookies.

For information about how you can change how your browser deals with cookies, please see the "Managing Cookies" section below.

### Which cookies do we use on this site and why?

The list below sets out the main cookies that we use on this site and what we use them for.

### Third Party Cookies

Some features used on this website may involve a cookie being sent to your computer by a third party. For example, if you view or listen to any embedded audio or video content you may be sent cookies from the site where the embedded content is hosted. Likewise, if you share any content on this website through social networks (for example by clicking a Facebook "like" button or a "Tweet" button) you may be sent cookies from these websites. We do not control the setting of these cookies so please check the websites of these third-parties for more information about their cookies and how to manage them.

### How to manage cookies

To make full use of this site, your device must be set to accept cookies otherwise some of its functionality (for example online shopping) may not work.

If you nevertheless want to restrict, block or disable cookies, you can do so by changing your browser settings. If you would like more specific information about how to change your browser settings, please visit www.allaboutcookies.org which has detailed information for each browser as well as more information about cookies in general.

### How to contact us

If you have any questions about this web site or our privacy policy, please contact us by writing to:

Digital Marketing  
Penguin Books Limited  
80 Strand  
London  
WC2R 0RL

or by telephoning: 020 7010 3000.

### Privacy Policy: Apps

This policy applies to software applications, enhanced ebooks and other similar digital products published by Penguin Books Limited, Dorling Kindersley Limited, Ladybird Books Limited, Frederick Warne & Co. Limited and Rough Guides Limited. Such products are referred to in this Policy as "Apps".

By using any of our Apps you accept the terms of this Privacy Policy.

### Our Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy is designed to give you useful information about how we collect and use personal information in our Apps.

### Personal Information

We will not collect any personal data from you unless you expressly provide it and we will only use that information for the purposes to which you have consented. We do not ask you to provide any more information than is reasonably necessary for the intended purposes, such as those listed below.

Generally, we do not disclose your personal information to third parties. We may have to sometimes, in which case we will inform you of our intention to do so when we collect the information and you will have the opportunity to consent to that or not. Except as described in this Privacy Policy, we do not maintain any personal information obtained from users through our Apps in a retrievable form.

The information that we collect and how we use it

Below are some examples of when we might request your information and how we will use it.

### User Content

If you provide comments or upload your own content to our Apps, we may ask you to provide your name and email address so that we know who posts which comment and to enable us to deal with any inappropriate, offensive or illegal material.

### Email and other contact details

You may wish to contact us from time to time by sending us emails or by filling in contact forms that may be accessible from our Apps. We will only use this information to respond to your query or suggestion.

### In-app purchasing

If you make an in-app purchase through one of our Apps, we will not collect any financial information from you and that information will remain with the relevant app store. However, we may collect information about which purchases have made so that we can ascertain which of our products are most popular and how we might improve our Apps in the future.

### Newsletters

We have several newsletters that keep readers up-to-date with information on our books, products, authors, events and offers. If you would like to subscribe to one of our newsletters, we will require you to send us your email address so that we can send the newsletter to you. We may also ask you to provide other information about yourself, such as your name, age, gender and location so that we can personalise your newsletters.

### Prize Promotions

We may run competitions and prize draws through our Apps for which, in addition to your answer or entry, we may require you to send us certain information, such as your name and email address. We will only use this information to administer the promotion and for any other purpose to which you consented at the time you entered the promotion.

### Anonymous aggregated analytics data

Many of our Apps use the Flurry analytics tool. This collects anonymous data which tell us how users interact with our Apps and we will analyse that data to help us decide how to build better Apps in the future.

If you wish to opt-out from Flurry analytics, please follow this link: http://www.flurry.com/resources/privacy.html

### How to contact us

If you have any questions about our Apps or our Privacy Policy, please contact us by writing to:

Digital Publishing  
Penguin Books Limited  
80 Strand  
London  
WC2R 0RL

or by telephoning: 020 7010 3000.

Last Updated: 6 November 2012
